Faisal Arshed

Software Engineer github.com/farshed mail@farshed.me (+92) 309 6855375

Full Stack Engineer with four years of experience. I thrive in small teams where I can make a high impact on the product from design to delivery. Interested in roles that offer extensive opportunities for learning and technical growth beyond my current expertise.

Work Experience

Senior Software Engineer

Jul 2022 - Present

SmashCloud

- Spearheaded the front-end development and collaborated on DevOps for a Fortune Global 500 venture in a lead engineering role.
- Developed crucial features for a widely adopted tenant turnover management system, streamlining operations for some of the top student housing owners across North America.

Software Engineer

Mar 2021 - Jun 2022

Pursue Today

- Developed pribox.io, a SaaS product for improving email deliverability, acting as its sole engineer during most of the MVP stage.
- Wrote automated planning and task scheduling services that closely interacted with SMTP and IMAP protocols.

Full Stack Engineer

Sep 2020 - Apr 2021

BookOtto

- Prototyped and developed the flagship MVP using React Native and GraphQL.
- Helped create and maintain the AWS backend and DevOps infrastructure.
- Developed solutions to streamline bureaucratic processes for the NYC real estate market.

React Native Developer

Mar 2019 - Dec 2019

MoneyWhere

- Developed core fintech MVP using React Native and Node.js.
- Implemented a virtual currency system, geolocation services and advanced map capabilities.

Education

BS in Computer Science

2016 - 2020

PMAS University of Arid Agriculture

Skills

 JavaScript
 React
 Next.js
 React Native
 Node.js
 AWS
 Rust
 Dart
 Flutter

GraphQL | gRPC | MongoDB | PostgreSQL